Peter Ataras

503-536-3734

About Me

I have been working in kitchens for eight years. I've decided to return to school to pursue a new career. However, I need to pay for school. I am looking for a job to maintain for the entirety of my 2-4 years of schooling. I am seeking an employer who can be flexible with scheduling during my schooling. In my free time I enjoy seeing family, traveling, camping and spending time in the kitchen.

Education

I Graduated one year early from Benson High School in Portland Oregon with high honors and a major in auto mechanics.

As I lacked finances for culinary school I decided to buy all the culinary textbooks and study the basics on my own. I would pick a recipe, study, practice, and repeat until it was perfect. Je parle un peu français, and I hablo español moderado.

Experience

• Petite Provence -3420 NE Sandy Blvd, Portland, OR 97232

May 2015-July 2016 I worked as a baker at Petite Provence on Alberta. My responsibilities ranged from morning bake where I prepared all daily cakes and pastries to closing or opening cashier. I learned how to interact with customers and front of house basics.

July 2016- April 2017 I worked at La provence on Division. This was the main bakery for Petite Provence. Here I worked with breads, cakes, cookies, laminated doughs, chocolates, and mousses. I learned dough and bakery basics which sparked my interest in the kitchen.

April 2017- August 2017 I started on the breakfast line making salads, omelets, and eggs at Petite Provence on Division. It threw me into an entirely new environment moving at a very fast pace, I loved it. I also worked dinner where I learned many basics of cooking including basic plating techniques.

August 2017-December 2017 I worked in the kitchen at Petite Provence in Lake Oswego. There I did anything ranging from running prep to leading the line during the night. This has taught me how to self manage and multi-task.

July 2018- January 2019 I returned to their Sandy location to work breads and laminated doughs.

<u>Cadillac Cafe</u>-1801 NE Broadway St, Portland, OR 97232

August 2017- April 2018 I worked on the line at Cadillac Cafe. Here I learned consistency, teamwork, mise en place, and speed. In addition I perfected my egg cookery.

• Serratto-2112 NW Kearney St, Portland, OR 97210

April 2018- June 2019

While working here I worked every line position. This includes pizzas, pantry, sauté, and grill. I was a full time grill cook and quickly learned temperatures and handling of a wide variety of proteins. I memorized everything on these stations and began to cook with muscle memory. This was a very high paced and large output environment where I was in charge of preparing my station every day. In addition to this I began to take on leadership tasks such as butchery, expediting the line, soup making, and training new cooks.

• Mcmenamins Zeus Cafe-303 SW 12th Ave, Portland, OR 97205

March 2019-July 2019, September 2019- January 2020, September 2020-March 2021 I was offered a job here by Chef Alexander, the former chef of Clark Lewis. I was hired as a Sous chef for the morning shift. My responsibilities ranged from; running service, opening breakfast, lunch, dinner, managing prep, and ensuring the kitchen was ready for a full day of service. This restaurant had two kitchens, one open kitchen upstairs and one prep kitchen in the basement. Not only did this help refine my management skills it improved my presentation and professionalism.

• Imperial-410 SW Broadway, Portland, OR 97205

September 2019- January 2020

During my stay at Imperial I've had a chance to work every station from plancha, sauté, pantry, and our massive wood fired grill. Here I've further refined the basics of my culinary skills. While working under a very fast paced, yet detail orientated line I always ensure every dish is made to the very best of my ability. I was promoted to lead line cook about half a month before covid broke out. I was laid off during the restaurant closures.

Stagés

I have stagéd multiple times at <u>The Willow</u> located at 2005 SE 11th Ave, Portland, OR 97214. Here I was able to learn more advanced plating techniques and focus on refining my knife skills. Willow also gave me the opportunity to focus on perfection and precision in every aspect of the kitchen.

I was at <u>Bijou</u> for four days at 10 Rue Dancourt, 75018 Paris, France. Here I learned pizza and kitchen presentation for guests. I learned how to make amazing pizza dough and how to work a high temperature wood fired oven.

Andina

April 2021 - October 2021

At Andina I worked under Chef Alexander Diestra as a Sous chef. I helped build and refine menus during the reopening of Andina. In addition I helped shape the work environment and individuals there in order to create a happy and productive workplace. With the guidance of Alexander I also helped create and refine the new pastry program of Andina.

Eem

December 2021-present

At Eem I worked as a pm line cook. This is a very fast paced environment in which we regularly sell around 20 thousand dollars a day. Despite such a busy atmosphere our goal has always been

less than 20 minute ticket times. Here I have spent the past 6 months refining my skills on the wok. In addition I have spent my time here learning the key flavors of Thai cuisine and expanding my understanding of its main components. Eem is also a BBQ restaurant so I have had the chance to learn how to properly work a smoker and many techniques to serve good BBQ.

School

December 2021-present

During my time at Eem I have also been going to college full time. I am going for a Computer Information Science degree. I hope to use this degree in the future to join the programming industry. During these classes I have had in-depth experience and practice with Microsoft Word, Office, and Excel. My end goal is to combine my kitchen experience with my programming knowledge in order to develop programs to help run kitchens in a more efficient manner.

• <u>Travel</u>

July 2019- September 2019

I traveled to see new things and experience new cultures. However, the main focus was food. During my travels I saw many new things that gave me a vast range of ideas to implement into the kitchen. I went to San Jose, Norway, Sweden, Netherlands, France, Spain, and Guyana.

References

- Paschal Tissuer Executive Pastry Chef and part owner of Petite Provence 503-267-9545
 - Efrain Cardenas Executive Chef of Petite Provence 503-515-6360
 - Gennaro Nastri Owner and chef of Bijou
 +33 6 34 31 20 69
 - Doug Weiler Chef and owner of Willow 631-478-8414
 - John Pickett 814-933-8872
 - Dan Hegwood Sous Chef at Cadillac Cafe 503-984-1645
 - Phil Cooper Head Chef at Cadillac Cafe 503-997-8555
 - Alexander Diestra Executive chef of Andina

503-860-9215

- Brian Fenicle Sous Chef of Serratto
 503-753-0981
- Matthew Jarrell Former Director of culinary operations of Paley hospitality and Executive Chef of Imperial 971-570-8699